Guide to the Phillip C. Keenan Papers, 1925-1999 RG.40.186
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
Phillip C. Keenan Papers
1925-1999
RG.40.186
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
9.6 Cubic feet
The Philip C. Keenan Papers contain correspondence and subject files on spectral classification and MIRA variables. Philip Keenan was a professor of astronomy at the Ohio State University.
(8) cartons
Keenan, Philip C. (Philip Childs), 1908-
Arrangement of Materials
Materials are arranged in the order received.
Acquisitions Information
Accession Number UA.1995.0166: Philip C. Keenan
Access to Materials
Materials in this collection are available for patron research, but may be used only in the University Archives Reading Room. Some materials in this collection may be stored off-site, and are only available if requested 72 hours in advance of your visit. Contact the University Archives for more information.
Biographical Note
Philip Childs Keenan (1908-2000) was a professor of astronomy at the Ohio State University from 1946 to 1976. He, along with co-author W.W. Morgan, developed the M-K Standard of stellar spectral classification in an atlas published in 1943.
Scope and Contents
The Philip C. Keenan Papers contain correspondence and subject files on spectral classification and MIRA variables.
Related Materials
Ohio State University Archives Biographical File
Phillip C. Keenan
Keenan, Philip C. (Philip Childs), 1908-; Ohio State University--Faculty.; Ohio State University--History.; Ohio State University. Department of Astronomy.; Astronomy--Study and teaching (Higher)--Ohio--Columbus; College teachers--Ohio--Columbus; Stars--Spectra--Research
- Accession Number UA.1995.0166, 1925-1999; 9.6 Cubic feet; (8) cartons
  - Correspondence, 1938-1995
    - ASP Review – Spectral Classification – Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Astronomical Illustrations-Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Atlas of Late Type Spectra – Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Carbon Stars – Correspondence, 1957, 1960, 1962, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence (4 folders), 1938-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence- Catalog of Spectral Types, 1988-1989 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence – "M", 1946-1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence-Morgan, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence "N", 1950-1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence "O" to "R", 1947-1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence "S" to "V", 1951-1954, 1988-1989 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Correspondence "W" to "Z", 1952-1990 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Mira Variables – Correspondence, 1961-1991 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Mira Variables – Morris Manuscript Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Refrigeration of Spectographs, 1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Spectographs – Comparison Sources, 1968 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Spectral Classification – Correspondence (2 folders), 1961-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Spectral Classification Standards Correspondence, 1981-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - SMR Stars Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Strasbourg Colloquium- Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
    - Variable Stars Correspondence, 1961, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0001)
  - Subject Files, 1932-1999
    - AAS Publication Costs, 1961-1962 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - AAVSO, 1953, 1955, 1960 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - ASP Review – Spectral Classification, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Astronomers, 1979, 1990, 1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Astronomoers – Biographies, 1994 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Aura, 1948-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - By Ord, 1947-1949, 1990 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Cerro Tololo Referee's Reports, 1974-1986 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - CH, CN Measurements on Ce Plates, 1957 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - CH Stars, 1941-1951 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Classification – Teachers, 1994-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Clusters Spectral Types, 1969, 1974 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Colloquium IAU #106-Evaluation of Peculiar Red Giants, 1986-1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Colloquium Notes, 1932, 1939, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Galactic Clusters – NGC188, 1960, 1964, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Bibliography of Stellar Spectra, 1959 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Colloquium 106 Review Paper Classification, 1989 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Commission – Radial Velocities, 1965 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Commission 24 – Spectroscopic parallaxes, Working Group, 1969 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Commission 29 Working Group on Standard Stars, 1979-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Commission No. 29 Stellar Spectra, 1962-1981 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - IAU Subcommission 296 Molecular Bands, 1946, 1953, 1990 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Imhoff, Cathy, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Keenau Pitts – Luminosity of Supergiants in Open Clusters, 1984-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Linear Diameters of Stars, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Mendoza Symposium, 1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Miscellaneous, 1941-1999 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - NGC – 188 Radial Velocities, 1957, 1960 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - NSF Referee Reports, 1969-1994 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Open Clusters with Late Type Giants in Foreground, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Prizes and Awards, 1976-1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Public Talks, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - R CrB Magnitudes, 1955-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - R CrB Radial Velocity, 1959 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Radio Talks, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - RA's Referee's Reports, 1978-1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Recommendations, 1975-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Referee's Reports, 1956-1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Referee's Reports – A.J., 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Referee's Reports – Ap.J Letters, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Referee's Reports – ASP, 1976-1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Referee's Reports- Astronomy and Astrophysics, 1971-1979 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Reidel- Manuscript Forms, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Reports – Yerkes, 1937-1941 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Research Corporation – Referee's Reports, 1973-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Reviews, 1952-1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Revised Classification of Red Carbon Stars, 1992-1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Site Data, 1952 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Sky and Telescope, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Stellar Taxonomy, 1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Space Telescope Science Institute, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Talks-Invitations, 1959, 1971 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Television, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Thesis Appraisals, 1973-1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Travel Information, 1971-1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Type Styles, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Universities, 1956 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - Universities-Living Quarters, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1979 (Box UA.1995.0166.0002)
  - Spectral Classification, 1933-1994
    - λ λ 7665, 7964, KI Intensities, 1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - 1983 Luminosity Calibration – Statistical Parallaxes, 1983-1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - AAS Bloomington, 1975 March (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Bright Giants – Class II, 1971-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Cerro Tololo – McNeil Project – South Galactic Pole, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Classification – Stars with Abnormal Colors, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Classification of Stars with Discrepant Huk Luminosities, 1973 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Comendium Vol. 6 – Red Giants Ch. 11, 1957-1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Correlation of Spectroscopic and Photometric Classification, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - G and K Stars with Strong Hydrogen Lines, 1954 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - G, K Classification – Metallacity, 1971 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - G, K Classification on Coude' Spectrograms, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - HD 101065 – Pryzbylski's Star, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars, 1951-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars – H-R Diagram, 1952-1953 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars – Luminosities, 1951-1952 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars – Reports, 1951 June (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars – Reproductions, 1961 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - High Velocity Stars – Space Motions, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Hydrogen – Balmer Lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - HR Diagram – Correspondence, 1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - IAU Symposium #80 HR Diagram – Manuscript, 1977-1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Infrared Nitrogen Lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Infrared OI Lines, 1948 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Infrared OI Lines Abundance Computations, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Infrared OI Lines – Measurements of Total Absorption, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Infrared Spectra: I-Z plates, 1953 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Kulper Compendium – vol. 3, 1959-1967 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Line Identifications – Correspondence, 1963-1981 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Line Intensities on Coude' Plates, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosities by Line Widths, 1974-1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosities – Early Type Stars, 1982, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosities from Hd, 1979 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration – Binary Stars, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration By Hak Emission Wilson – Bappu, 1956, 1973 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration – Hyades, 1967, 1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration – IAU Symposium #54, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration of Stars with Discrepant K-Line Luminosities, 1975-1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration Reductions to Constant Volumes, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration – Statistically Parallax Program, 1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Calibration – Trigonometric Parallaxes, 1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Class Calibration – Correspondence, 1974–1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Classification – Statistical Parallaxes, 1968 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Luminosity Effects in Multiplets of Fe and Ti, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Manuscript – Could Classification of Semi Barium Stars, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Mean Parallaxes, 1991 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Metal – Poor Stars, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Paschen Lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Peculiar Stars – Handbuk Der Physick, 1956-1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Preliminary Coude Classifcation, 1973 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Report – Spectroscopic Parallaxes – Working Group of IAU Commission #24, 1969 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Resonance Line Program, 1957 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - RF 3328 – Al Classification Project, 1971 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - RF Project 693 Classification K3-MI, 1955-1956, 1973 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Slitless Classification – Sanduleak Workshop, 1991 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Slitless Spectograms – Reproductions, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - SMR Classification, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - SMR Stars – Manuscript, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification - Monochromatic Photometry, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectrum – Temperature Relations, 1981-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Special Standards – Southern Stars, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Enlargement Blue Region, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Low Dispersion, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification - Low Dispersion IR, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Photoelectric, 1961 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Slitless Blue, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Slitless Red, 1963 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Spectrophometric, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Spectroscopic Binaries, 1979-1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Peculiar Stars, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – SUN, 1991 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Talks, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Type F, 1953 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Type G, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Types: G, K, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectral Classification – Visual Region, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectroscopic Absolute Magnitudes – Comparisons, 1936-1937 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectroscopy Astronomical – Britannica Article, 1966 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectrum – Color Relations, 1964, 1966 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spectrum – Luminosity Diagram, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Spitless Spectra – Warner and Swasey Schmidt, 1943-1946 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Stars with Discrepant Luminosities – BS 8924, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Stars with Discrepant K-Line Luminosities – Correspondence, 1973-1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Statistical Parallax Paper, 1981 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Statistical Parallax Program – Correspondence, 1979-1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Statistical of Spectral Types, 1963 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Stellar Spectra - Iµ Region, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Stellar Spectra Types – Faint Stars, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Stellar Spectra W Far Red, 1955-1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Strong CH Stars, 1951-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Strong CH Stars – BS 965, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants, 1952 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Correspondence, 1964-1994 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Super-Distribution, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Classification, 1948-1965 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Field Charts, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Lists, 1950-1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Morgan Paper, 1979 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Photometry, 1986 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Supergiants – Spectra, 1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Te- Spectral Type Paper, 1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Temperature Calibration Correspondence, 1981 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Trigonometric Parallaxes, 1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - TY Vir., 1957-1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Type G-Line Broadening, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Types G, K – Lists of Peculiar Stars, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - UV Spectra, 1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - Weak – CH Stars, 1951, 1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0003)
    - 22 Vol, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - +24°3902 comp lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Abundances: Meetings, 1966 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Abundances of Elements – Stellar, 1986 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Atlas of Spectra of Late Type Stars – Plates Manuscript, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Beanie Drake Scholarship, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - By Dre Paper – ASP meeting, 1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - CH, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - CoD - 33° 12241 MOIa, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Colloquium – Cool Stars with Excesses of Heavy Elements, 1983-1991 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Comets – Spectra, 1941 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Cordoba Symposium – Paper, 1972, 1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - CN Bands – Reproductions Small Scale – Blue, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Dwarfs – K,M, 1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Dwarfs – K,M By Dra Group, 1979-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Dwarfs – Luminosities, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Dwarfs – Type G, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Dwarfs – Type G – Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - E peg, A & C, 1955 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Estimates of Line Intensities, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Faint MK Standards Project, 1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Garrison Colloquium: MK Classification, 1981-1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Gg Camera, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Guest Night Talks, 1962-1974 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Colloquium # 47 MK Classification, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Commission – 29 – Reports, 1960-1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Commission 45 – Grenoble Notation Discussion, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Commission 45 – Reports, 1966-1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Commission 45 – Spectral Classification, 1960-1963, 1991-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Symposium #111 Calibration of Stellar Quantities, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Symposium #1 Them K Classification and its calibration, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IAU Symposium – Abundance Effects, 1974-1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - IUE, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Joint Commission for Spectroscopy, 1956 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Li 6708 – Abundance, 1974 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Marenin Tc Project, 1983-1986 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Maxima of Bands in Stellar Spectra, 1947 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Maxima of Spectral Lines, 1933 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Middletown Paper on Standards, 1991-1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - MK Standards, 1988 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - NOAA – Solar Flares, 1990 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - NSF, 1976-1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - NSF – RF – 711347 Classes II and IV, 1978-1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - NSSDC – National Space Science Data Center, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - N.Y. Academy of Sciences, 1957 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Observatories, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Oil Wells, 1964 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Ohio Neighborhood Astronomers, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Opacities from CN Bands, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - O.S.U., 1989 May (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Astronomy Department, 1962-1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Grad Requirements, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Graduate Schools, 1951 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Graduate Students, 1975-1980 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Insurance and Retirement, 1957, 1969 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Lab Supplies, 1962 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Maps, 1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - O.S.U. Physics Dept. – Graduate Work, 1960 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Press, 1957 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Public Relations, 1956 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Research Foundation, 1968, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OSU Speakers Rule, 1962, 1965 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - OWU, 1953, 1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Perkins Assistant, 1971 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Perkins Contributions and Reprints, 1969-1979 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Perkins Observatory, 1956-1957, 1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Perkins Observatory – History, 1987-1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - P Cas – Blue, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - P Cas Correspondence, 1956, 1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - P Cas – Infrared (Minimum), 1946, 1956 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - P Cas – Red Region, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - PCK Vita and Phonographs, 1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Personnel Astronomers, 1978-1986 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Red Stars, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Red Stars – Southern, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Red Stars in Associations, 1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Relations between Cool Star Groups, 1983 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Reports – Perkins, 1947-1987 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Revised MK Catalog – GKM, 1979-1990 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Revised MK System, 1973-1978 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - RF 4047 ALC Atlas of Spectra of Cool Stars – Publication, 1974-1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - RF 711347 Publication of Catalogs, 1983-1985 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - RF 71390 Applications of Spectral Catalog, 1980-1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - RW Cep-IR Wavelengths, Gd, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - RW Cephei, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral "Classification – Atlases, 1993 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification – Data Center, 1970-1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification – Programs, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification – Review in ARAA Vol. 11, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification – Standard Types, 1947, 1953, 1985, 1994 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Spectral Classification – UV Correspondence, 1982 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Stars – Rotation – Late Types, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Stars with Abnormal CN Intensities, 1954 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Stars with Composite Spectra, 1969-1995 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Stars with Shallow HϕK, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Strasbourg Colloquium Volume, 1974, 1989 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Strasbourg Paper – Yorka, Kennan, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Stellar Associations, 1966 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Strong – CN Stars, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Sub Dwarfs, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – CN Bands, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – Composition, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – BM Sco, 1984 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – BS 8752, 1970-1992 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants in Clusters, 1959, 1966, 1972 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants in Clusters: Luminosities, 1976 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants in LMC, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – Late Types – Colors, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants Late Types – Luminosities, 1970, 1977 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – Li 6708, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – Luminosities from Line Widths, 1975 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – Luminosity Calibration, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Supergiants – R Pup, 1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Total Absorption of Spectral Lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Tuscon MK Conference, 1992-1994 (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
    - Weak Line Stars, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0004)
  - Mira Variables, 1925-1987
    - β Pegasi, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - λ 4737 λ λ 4600-4900, 1956-1958 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - λλ 7300-7800 Bands (Long-Period Variables), 1948-1949 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - A10, 1967 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - A-Stars Spectral Types, 1939 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Cepheid Variable Stars, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - CH Cyg, 1953-1964 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Classification by Lines on Coude' Spectograms – Manuscript, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Classification – Cordoba, 1966 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Cool Stars – Atmospheres, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Comparison Stars for Mira Variables – Intensities of Balmer Lines, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Coude Classification – Paper – Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - CPD 56° 3586-Composite Spectrum, 1970 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Early Long Period Variables Blue Wavelengths, undated (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)
    - Early Long Period Variables – Enlargements, 1964 (Box UA.1995.0166.0005)